Guide to the Mary Deming 4-H Clippings MS 051
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Mary Deming 4-H Clippings
1952-1964
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Deming, Mary
MS 051
2.5 Linear Feet, 2 boxes
Mary A. (Milner) Deming was a graduate of UConn and former Associate Club Agent of New Haven County. In January 1953, Mary Deming began contributing to the "4-H Club Activies" column in the Danbury News-Times. These are clippings of her column up until 1964 with some gaps.
Conditions Governing Access
The original clippings are quite brittle. Access is restricted the photocopies.
Biographical / Historical
Mary Milner Deming joined 4-H at the age of 10, and was the leader of several local 4-H clubs in the Danbury area, a 4-H Camp Director, and Western Connecticut 4-H Camp cook.
Mary Deming earned a B.S. degree in Home Economics from UMass at Amherst and a M.S. degree in Elementary Education at WCSU, Danbury. She worked professionally as an Assistant County 4-H Club Agent in Worcester County in Massachusetts, in Butte County in California and in New Haven County, Connecticut. She was a teacher for 20 years in the Danbury, Connecticut school system. She taught 2nd, 3rd, 7th, 8th, and 9th grade and was a Fulbright Exchange teacher in Prescot England for the 1983-1984 school year. Robert "Bob" Deming and Mary Milner married in 1952. Robert Deming was County 4-H Club Agent in Fairfield County in Connecticut and was a source for much of the news that appeared in the weekly 4-H Club activities columns in the Bridgeport Sunday Post. All the Demings' children were 4-H members.
Howard Burr, the author of some of the 1952 and 1953 4-H Activities columns, was an employee of the Bridgeport Post.
Custodial History
Scrapbooks donated by Mary Deming in February of 2010.
Scope and Contents
The collection is made up of clippings from the Bridgeport Sunday Post, Newtown Bee and Danbury News. The clippings are the weekly news stories of 4-H Club activities in Fairfield County were written primarily by Mary Deming but some of the 1952 columns were written by Howard O. Burr. The columns contain news on club activities in Fairfield county, as well as other counties of the state. Several columns contain photographs of club members and events that were of particular interest at the time. Researchers should note a gap in the chronology between 1955 and 1960, and that 1960 is incomplete.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Clippings.; 4-H clubs; Agriculture -- United States -- History; Agriculture -- Connecticut; Fairfield County (Conn.) -- History; Burr, Howard; Deming, Mary; Danbury News.; Bridgeport Sunday Post; Newtown Bee
- Inventory
  - 1952 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    1952: Mar 9, 16, 23, 30 | Apr 6, 13, 20, 27 | May 4, 11, 18, 25 | Jun 18, 15, 22, 29 | July 6, 13, 20, 27 | Aug 3, 10, 17, 24, 31 | Sep 7, 14, 21, 28 | Oct 5, 12, 19, 26 | Nov 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Dec 7, 14, 28
  - 1953 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 2)
    1953: Jan 4, 11, 18, 26 | Feb 8, 15, 22 | Mar 18, 15, 22, 29 | Apr 5, 12, 19, 26 | May 8, 10, 17, 24, 31 | Jun 7, 14, 21, 28 | Jul 5, 12, 20, 26 | Aug 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Sep 13, 20, 27 | Oct 4, 11, 18, 25 | Nov 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 | Dec 6, 13, 20, 28,
  - 1954 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 3)
    1954: Jan 3, 10, 17, 24, 31 | Feb 7, 14, 21, 28 | Mar 7, 1421, 29 | Apr 4, 11, 18, 25 | May 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Jun 13, 20, 27 | Jul 4, 11, 18, 25 | Aug 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 | Sep 5, 12, 19, 26 | Oct 3, 10, 17, 24 | Nov 7, 14, 21, 28 | Dec 5, 12, 19, 26
  - 1955 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
    1955: Jan 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Feb 6, 13, 20, 27 | Mar 6, 13, 29, 27 | Apr 3, 10, 17, 24 | May 1, 8, 15, 20, 22, 29 | Jun 6, 12, 19, 27 | Jul 3, 10, 17, 24 | Aug 14, 21, 28 | Sep 4, 11, 18, 25 | Oct 2, 10, 17, 23, 30 | Nov 6, 13, 20, 27 | Dec 5, 11
  - 1960 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
    1960: Mar 9 | Aug 8
  - 1962 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 6)
    1962: Mar 4, 18, 25 | Apr 15, 22, 29 | May 6, 13, 27 | Jun 10, 17, 24 | Jul 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 | Aug 5, 19 | Sep 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Oct 7, 15, 28 | Nov 4, 1, 25 | Dec 2, 9, 16, 23, 30
  - 1963 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 7)
    1963: Jan 6, 20 | Feb 10, 17 | Mar 3, 10, 17, 14, 31 | Apr 7, 28 | May 5, 12, 19, 27 | Jun 2, 9, 16, 23, 30 | Jul 7, 14, 21, 28 | Aug 4, 11, 18 | Sep 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 | Oct 6, 14, 20, 27 | Nov 3, 10, 17, 24 | Dec 1, 8, 15, 29
  - 1964 Clippings (Box 1, Folder 8)
    1964: Jan 1, 12, 19, 26 | Feb 2, 9, 16, 23 | Mar 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 | April 5, 12, 19, 26 | May 2, 21, 23, 30 | Jun 1, 8, 28 | Jul 5, 12, 19, 26 | Aug 2, 21, 23, 30 | Sep 6, 13, 20, 27 | Oct 4
  - Original Scrapbooks, 1952-1964 (Box 2)